Hello everyone and welcome to another great lesson here at EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod的另一堂精彩课程。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we've got an upper intermediate level lesson for you all.
我是Catherine，今天我们为大家准备了一节中高级课程。
That's right.
没错。
We're going to talk a little bit about business and specifically we are in a business meeting
我们要聊一点关于商务的话题，具体来说，我们正在开一个商务会议，
where we're trying to sell something to someone.
试图向某人推销东西。
That's right.
没错。
So you're going to hear a lot of talk about chocolate or in this case gourmet bonbons.
所以你会听到很多关于巧克力，或者更准确地说，是高级夹心巧克力的讨论。
Gourmet bonbons.
高级夹心巧克力。
This is another word for chocolate candies or candies.
这是巧克力糖果的另一种说法。
Okay.
好的。
So a bonbon is kind of like round usually, right?
所以bonbon通常是圆形的，对吧？
Usually, yes.
通常是的。
Okay.
好的。
All right.
行。
So let's get started and listen to today's dialogue.
那我们开始吧，听今天的对话。
We'll be back in a moment.
我们一会儿就回来。
I'm glad you could find time to meet with me, Mr. Johnson.
很高兴您能抽出时间见我，约翰逊先生。
I can't think of a nicer environment for our meeting today.
我想不出比这更适合我们今天会议的环境了。
The ambience here is lovely.
这里的气氛真不错。
No problem.
没问题。
If possible, I always combine business with pleasure.
如果可能的话，我总是把工作和娱乐结合起来。
Now let's hear more about these chocolates you're offering.
现在让我们多听听你提供的这些巧克力吧。
Well, as you know, I have recently become the sole distributor for Granger's gourmet
嗯，如你所知，我最近成为了格兰杰美食
bonbons here in the United States.
夹心巧克力在美国的独家经销商。
They're a new manufacturer and are looking to break into the luxury market.
他们是一家新制造商，正试图打入奢侈品市场。
Naturally, your restaurant sprang into my mind immediately.
自然，我立刻就想到了你的餐厅。
I think your brand exemplifies many of the same traits as Granger's and serving these
我认为你的品牌体现了许多与格兰杰相同的特质，提供这些
chocolates would really add to your reputation for providing elegant, luxurious, first-class
巧克力真的能提升你提供优雅、奢华、一流
dining.
餐饮的声誉。
Hmm.
嗯。
Sounds interesting.
听起来挺有意思。
Gourmet chocolates.
美食巧克力。
Where are they produced?
它们是在哪里生产的？
Belgium?
比利时？
Actually, the factory is located in Scotland.
实际上，工厂位于苏格兰。
Really?
真的吗？
I didn't think they were known for their luxury chocolate production.
我没想到他们以生产奢侈巧克力而闻名。
That's what makes this such a fantastic opportunity.
这正是为什么这是一个绝佳的机会。
The government is 100% supportive of creating new export markets and has guaranteed a low
政府百分之百支持开拓新的出口市场，并已保证低
tariff for all wholesale orders of over 1,000 units.
所有超过1000件批发订单的关税。
They've also reduced the red tape involved at customs as well.
他们还简化了海关的繁琐手续。
Here, I brought these especially for you.
来，我特意给你带了这些。
Try one.
尝一个。
Oh, thanks.
哦，谢谢。
Hmm.
嗯。
Creamy texture.
口感细腻。
Very smooth.
非常顺滑。
Unique, aren't they?
很独特，对吧？
I bet you've never tasted anything like it.
我敢说你从没尝过这样的味道。
Quality is assured as I personally visit the factory to make sure no one's cutting corners
质量有保证，因为我亲自去工厂检查，确保没人偷工减料
with the ingredients.
在原料上。
Only the creme de la creme make it through inspection.
只有最顶尖的才能通过检验。
Yes.
是的。
Very interesting flavors.
味道很有趣。
Slightly spicy.
有点辣。
Hmm.
嗯。
Very unique, that's for sure.
确实很独特。
Exactly what are the ingredients?
具体是什么原料？
I have it on highest authority that this traditional secret recipe has been handed down in the
我得到最高权威的消息，这个传统秘方已经传下来了
Granger family for generations.
在格兰杰家族世代相传。
I'm sure you can keep a secret.
我相信你能保守秘密。
Buttermilk, cacao beans, sugar, and haggis.
酪乳、可可豆、糖，还有哈吉斯。
What's haggis?
哈吉斯是什么？
It's a traditional Scottish delicacy.
这是一种传统的苏格兰美食。
You take sheep's liver, heart, and lung and stuff it inside the sheep's stomach.
你把羊肝、羊心和羊肺塞进羊胃里。
I'll get back to you.
我回头再联系你。
Mr. Johnson.
约翰逊先生。
All right.
好吧。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So a lot of interesting vocab there.
所以那里有很多有趣的词汇。
The guy was trying to convince them about these chocolates but it turned out to be something
那家伙试图说服他们这些巧克力很好，但结果却是有点
a little bit strange and we'll talk about that in a little while.
奇怪的东西，我们稍后会讨论这个。
Before we get into that, why don't we take a look at seven key words that we have prepared
在我们进入正题之前，不如先看看我们今天为你们准备的七个关键词
for you today on Language Takeaway.
在“语言小贴士”环节。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
Okay.
好的。
So we've divided Language Takeaway into two parts today.
所以今天我们把“语言小贴士”分成两部分。
The first part is all about business and manufacturing.
第一部分全是关于商业和制造业的。
So what's our first word, Marco?
那么，马可，我们的第一个词是什么？
All right.
好的。
So I talked about being the sole distributor for this company called Granger's Gourmet
所以我提到了我是这家叫格兰杰美食的公司的独家经销商。
Bonbons.
夹心巧克力。
Okay.
好的。
A distributor.
经销商。
Okay.
好的。
This is a person or a company and the distributor is someone who distributes or sells a product,
经销商是指一个人或一家公司，负责分销或销售产品。
right?
对吧？
Right.
对。
So the factory will make them.
所以工厂负责生产。
He will get all these goods from the factory and then he will be the one that gives it
他从工厂拿到所有货物，然后负责把这些货物送到不同的零售店。
to the different retail stores.
送到不同的零售店。
So he can have many clients and he is the main person who you get it from.
所以他可以有很多客户，他是你拿货的主要渠道。
So obviously they don't get it directly from the factory.
显然，他们不是直接从工厂拿货的。
Okay.
好的。
So this person, a distributor or a company, is in the middle of the transaction.
所以这个人，经销商或公司，处于交易的中间环节。
On one side there is the manufacturer and on the other side there is the retail market
一边是制造商，另一边是零售市场。
or stores.
或者商店。
Exactly.
没错。
And as you said, that's our second key word today, manufacturer.
正如你所说，这是我们今天的第二个关键词，制造商。
Okay.
好的。
Manufacturer, again, is a person or a company that makes a good.
制造商，同样，是指生产商品的人或公司。
So for example, a television manufacturer makes TV.
比如，电视机制造商生产电视机。
It's like a factory.
就像工厂一样。
Exactly.
没错。
So they manufacture things.
所以他们制造东西。
They make them.
他们生产它们。
All right.
好的。
So we've got distributors who are moving goods.
所以我们有经销商在运输货物。
We have manufacturers who are making them.
我们有制造商在生产它们。
But what happens when we want to move a good out of a country?
但当我们想把货物运出国外时，会发生什么？
Okay.
好的。
So that is our third word for today.
这就是我们今天的第三个词。
Usually in customs, we have to pay a tariff for these goods or a tax.
通常在海关，我们必须为这些货物支付关税或税款。
Okay.
好的。
So a tariff is a special kind of tax that you pay when you are trying to export or send
所以关税是一种特殊的税，当你试图出口或把在国内生产的货物运到国外时，你需要支付。
outside of your country goods that you've made in that country.
把在国内生产的货物运到国外时。
So for example, if I make 100 TVs in America, but I want to sell these TVs to someone in
比如，如果我在美国生产了100台电视机，但我想把这些电视机卖给墨西哥的某人。
Mexico, I have to pay a tariff.
我就得支付关税。
I have to pay like $10 to the government that allows me to send these out of the country.
我得向政府支付大约10美元，才能允许我把这些货物运出国外。
That's right.
没错。
So that is a tariff.
这就是关税。
And now when he was talking about tariffs and how the government is reducing the tariffs
现在，当他谈到关税以及政府如何降低关税来激励商业时。
in order to motivate a business, he talked about also that the government is reducing
他还提到政府正在减少。
or cutting the red tape.
或者削减繁文缛节。
Okay.
好的。
So he says, listen, they've also reduced the red tape involved at customs.
所以他说，听着，他们还减少了海关的繁文缛节。
So this means that before they were encountering some problems at customs, because customs,
这意味着以前他们在海关遇到了一些问题，因为海关。
you know, there's a lot of paperwork, there's a lot of taxes, there's a lot of information
你知道，有很多文书工作，很多税款，很多信息。
you have to provide.
你必须提供。
It's a hassle.
很麻烦。
A lot of paperwork.
很多文书工作。
Right.
对。
So this kind of paperwork, bureaucracy, this is called red tape in English.
所以这种文书工作、官僚作风，在英语中被称为繁文缛节。
For example, I would love to get a visa for my foreign husband, but there's a lot of red
比如，我很想给我外国丈夫办签证，但有很多繁文缛节。
tape.
有很多工作要做。
There's a lot of work that we have to do.
有很多官僚程序要走。
There's a lot of bureaucratic processes that you have to do.
All right.
好的。
So red tape, this means a lot of paperwork, a lot of work that you have to do.
所以繁文缛节，意味着很多文书工作，很多你必须做的工作。
Okay.
好的。
So those are our key words that are related to business.
这些就是与商业相关的关键词。
Now let's move on to a couple of different adjectives.
现在我们来谈谈几个不同的形容词。
The first one, when he talked about chocolates, he said elegant.
第一个，当他谈到巧克力时，他说优雅。
He said that something is elegant.
他说某样东西很优雅。
Okay.
好的。
Elegant.
优雅。
This is a great adjective.
这是一个很棒的形容词。
You're going to see this on a lot of luxury brand items.
你会在很多奢侈品牌商品上看到它。
Elegance means something is elegant if it is classy, if it looks really good and rich.
优雅意味着某样东西如果很高级、看起来很好且奢华，就是优雅的。
Or you could say that dress is very elegant, that mink coat is very elegant.
或者你可以说那条裙子很优雅，那件貂皮大衣很优雅。
Okay.
好的。
This is a positive thing.
这是正面的评价。
So something that looks kind of expensive at times as well.
所以有时也指看起来有点贵的东西。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
Another word that means looking expensive or elegant is luxurious.
另一个表示看起来昂贵或优雅的词是豪华的。
Okay.
好的。
So luxurious comes from the noun luxury.
所以豪华的来自名词奢侈品。
That's right.
没错。
Luxury, luxurious.
豪华，奢华的。
So we can say that the executive suites at this hotel are very luxurious.
所以我们可以说这家酒店的行政套房非常奢华。
They have a jacuzzi, a king-size bed, expensive silk sheets.
它们有按摩浴缸、特大号床、昂贵的丝绸床单。
The best quality materials.
最优质的材料。
So you can say that elegant and luxurious kind of go hand in hand.
所以你可以说优雅和奢华是相辅相成的。
That's right.
没错。
Although elegant, you usually say about someone or their clothing or even a car, but luxurious
虽然优雅通常用来形容某人、他们的衣服甚至一辆车，但奢华
is more like a place or an object.
更像是指一个地方或物品。
Okay, good.
好的。
And then we have one final word that also describes something that is very rare or very
然后我们还有一个词，用来描述非常稀有或非常
good and rich, a delicacy.
好且丰富的东西，即珍馐。
Yeah, actually this one is a noun, it's a thing.
是的，实际上这是一个名词，指一种东西。
So we can say that this is a Scottish delicacy or what are the delicacies in your country?
所以我们可以说这是苏格兰的珍馐，或者你们国家有什么珍馐？
So delicacy is something that's special.
所以珍馐是特别的东西。
Okay.
好的。
So for example, you've told me that in Ecuador, there are some interesting food delicacies.
比如，你告诉过我，在厄瓜多尔有一些有趣的食物珍馐。
Delicacies?
珍馐？
Little animals.
小动物。
Yeah.
是的。
For example, guinea pigs.
比如，豚鼠。
So it's not really a delicacy, although kind of because guinea pigs are expensive comparatively
所以它不完全是珍馐，尽管有点算，因为豚鼠相对
to chickens, for example.
比如鸡来说比较贵。
So it is considered to be something that you only eat on special occasions.
所以它被认为是一种只在特殊场合才吃的东西。
Right.
对。
And in East Asia, many people consider shark's fin soup to be a delicacy.
在东亚，很多人认为鱼翅汤是珍馐。
Right.
对。
It's a special dish.
它是一道特别的菜。
So we can say that it's usually about food and it's rare, something that's rare or special
所以我们可以说它通常指食物，而且很稀有，是稀有或特别
or also can be very expensive.
的东西，也可能很贵。
That's right, a delicacy.
没错，珍馐。
Okay.
好的。
So a lot of great interesting words on language takeaway.
语言学习环节有很多有趣的好词。
Why don't we move on now to fluency builder?
我们不如继续到流利度提升环节？
Fluency builder.
流利度提升。
This first phrase is actually something I try to do as often as possible, but it's usually
第一个短语其实是我尽量常做的事，但通常
very difficult.
很难做到。
I combine business with pleasure.
我把工作和娱乐结合起来。
Right.
对。
To combine business with pleasure.
把工作和娱乐结合起来。
Now this is a whole phrase and this talks about doing business, but at the same time,
这是一个完整的短语，指的是做生意，但同时
doing it in a fun way or an interesting way.
以有趣或好玩的方式进行。
Right.
对。
And pleasure here means something that is fun or entertainment even.
这里的娱乐指的是有趣或甚至消遣的东西。
So for example, going out to dinner with your company is a way to combine business with
比如，和公司同事出去吃饭是一种把工作和娱乐
pleasure.
结合起来的方式。
All right.
好的。
Or meeting a client at a bar is combining business with pleasure.
或者在酒吧见客户也是把工作和娱乐结合起来。
So you're combining things that are fun and things that are work related.
所以你把有趣的事情和工作相关的事情结合在一起。
Right.
对。
Because you can have a business meeting in a boardroom or in a business or in a meeting
因为你可以在会议室或商务场所开会，
room, but if you have the same business meeting at a bar where you're talking and laughing,
但如果你在酒吧开同样的商务会议，边聊边笑，
but also at the same time talking business, then you're combining business with pleasure.
同时谈生意，那你就是在把工作和娱乐结合起来。
That's right.
没错。
And now for our second phrase, it's more about cheating, right?
现在第二个短语，更多是关于作弊，对吧？
Somebody that is cheating or maybe not doing things correctly.
有人作弊或做事不规矩。
They are cutting corners.
他们在偷工减料。
That's right.
没错。
So cutting corners is another way to say cheating.
所以偷工减料是作弊的另一种说法。
For example, I've seen people, students cutting corners with their studies.
比如，我见过学生，在学习上偷工减料。
You think about cutting corners, it means that you're not going the long way.
想想偷工减料，意思是你没有走正道。
You're cutting, you're cheating by going the shorter way.
你通过走捷径来作弊。
You're taking a shortcut.
你在走捷径。
Taking a shortcut.
走捷径。
So for example, instead of studying for that final test in math, some people write the
比如，有些人为了数学期末考试不学习，而是把
formulas on their hands.
公式写在手上。
This is a way to cut corners.
这是一种偷工减料的方式。
Instead of studying, you actually cheat by putting it on your hand, making it easier.
不学习，而是通过写在手上作弊，让自己轻松点。
So to cut corners is to cheat or to try to take the shortcut, but it kind of has a negative
所以偷工减料就是作弊或试图走捷径，但它有点负面
connotation, right?
含义，对吧？
Oh, definitely.
哦，当然。
So most people will say, don't cut corners.
所以大多数人会说，别偷工减料。
In the end, it's not worth it.
到头来不值得。
Right.
对。
And for our final phrase, we have one that it's in French.
最后一个短语，是法语的。
So this one is in French, but it's also a very common English phrase.
所以这个是法语的，但也是一个很常见的英语短语。
That's why we're going to teach it to you.
这就是为什么我们要教给你。
The creme de la creme.
精英中的精英。
Okay.
好的。
So literally, in translated from French, that means the cream of the cream.
所以字面上，从法语翻译过来，意思是奶油中的奶油。
Right.
对。
In English, we would say that it's the best of the best.
在英语中，我们会说这是“顶尖中的顶尖”。
The best of the best.
顶尖中的顶尖。
The very top.
最顶级的。
So that's what this phrase means.
所以这就是这个短语的意思。
The best of the best.
顶尖中的顶尖。
The very top.
最顶级的。
The most excellent.
最优秀的。
So you could say, Harvard University attracts the creme de la creme of American high school
所以你可以说，哈佛大学吸引了美国高中生的“顶尖精英”
students.
学生。
Okay.
好的。
So the very best of American high school students.
所以就是美国高中生中最优秀的那批。
All right.
好了。
So that phrase, it's in French, but you can say it in English, right?
所以这个短语是法语的，但你可以在英语中说，对吧？
Like fiance, for example.
比如“未婚夫”这个词。
Fiance.
未婚夫。
Creme de la creme.
顶尖精英。
So those are the words that we've stolen from French and we use in English.
所以这些是我们从法语中借来并在英语中使用的词。
So don't worry about how you pronounce it in English.
所以不用担心在英语中怎么发音。
We just say creme de la creme.
我们直接说“顶尖精英”。
Okay.
好的。
So why don't we listen to this dialogue for the last time, and we'll be back in just a
那我们最后再听一遍这段对话，我们一会儿就回来。
bit.
一会儿见。
I'm glad you could find time to meet with me, Mr. Johnson.
我很高兴你能抽出时间见我，约翰逊先生。
I can't think of a nicer environment for our meeting today.
我想不出比这更适合我们今天会议的环境了。
The ambience here is lovely.
这里的气氛很宜人。
No problem.
没问题。
If possible, I always combine business with pleasure.
如果可能的话，我总是把工作和娱乐结合起来。
Now let's hear more about these chocolates you're offering.
现在让我们多听听你提供的这些巧克力。
Well, as you know, I have recently become the sole distributor for Granger's Gourmet
嗯，如你所知，我最近成为了格兰杰美食
Bonbons here in the United States.
夹心巧克力在美国的独家经销商。
They're a new manufacturer and are looking to break into the luxury market.
他们是一家新制造商，正寻求打入奢侈品市场。
Naturally, your restaurant sprang into my mind immediately.
自然，我立刻就想到了你的餐厅。
I think your brand exemplifies many of the same traits as Granger's, and serving these
我认为你的品牌体现了与格兰杰许多相同的特质，提供这些
chocolates would really add to your reputation for providing elegant, luxurious, first-class
巧克力会真正提升你提供优雅、豪华、一流
dining.
餐饮的声誉。
Hmm, sounds interesting.
嗯，听起来很有趣。
Gourmet chocolates.
美食巧克力。
Where are they produced?
它们在哪里生产？
Belgium?
比利时？
Actually, the factory is located in Scotland.
实际上，工厂位于苏格兰。
Really?
真的吗？
I didn't think they were known for their luxury chocolate production.
我没想到他们以生产豪华巧克力闻名。
That's what makes this such a fantastic opportunity.
这就是为什么这是一个绝佳的机会。
The government is 100% supportive of creating new export markets and has guaranteed a
政府百分之百支持开拓新的出口市场，并已保证
low tariff for all wholesale orders of over 1,000 units.
对所有超过1000件的批发订单征收低关税。
They've also reduced the red tape involved at customs as well.
他们还减少了海关的繁琐手续。
Here, I brought these especially for you.
这里，我特意为你带了这些。
Try one.
尝一个。
Oh, thanks.
哦，谢谢。
Hmm, hmm.
嗯，嗯。
Creamy texture.
奶油般的口感。
Very smooth.
非常顺滑。
Unique, aren't they?
很独特，对吧？
I bet you've never tasted anything like it.
我打赌你从未尝过类似的东西。
Quality is assured as I personally visit the factory to make sure no one's cutting corners
质量有保证，因为我亲自去工厂确保没有人
with the ingredients.
在原料上偷工减料。
Only the creme de la creme make it through inspection.
只有顶尖中的顶尖才能通过检验。
Yes, very interesting flavors.
是的，非常有趣的味道。
Slightly spicy.
略带辛辣。
Hmm, very unique, that's for sure.
嗯，非常独特，这点是肯定的。
Exactly what are the ingredients?
具体成分是什么？
I have it on highest authority that this traditional secret recipe has been handed down in the
我得到最高权威的消息，这个传统秘密配方已经在
Granger family for generations.
格兰杰家族传承了几代人。
I'm sure you can keep a secret.
我相信你能保守秘密。
Buttermilk, cacao beans, sugar, and haggis.
酪乳、可可豆、糖和哈吉斯。
Haggis.
哈吉斯。
What's haggis?
哈吉斯是什么？
It's a traditional Scottish delicacy.
这是一种传统的苏格兰美食。
You take sheep's liver, heart, and lung and stuff it inside the sheep's stomach.
你把羊肝、羊心和羊肺塞进羊胃里。
I'll get back to you.
我回头再联系你。
Mr. Johnson?
约翰逊先生？
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now this Scottish delicacy.
所以现在这个苏格兰美食。
What is this haggis?
这个哈吉斯是什么？
Haggis.
哈吉斯。
Okay, haggis, I've never actually eaten it.
好的，哈吉斯，我其实从来没吃过。
It does sound pretty disgusting.
听起来确实挺恶心的。
It's a Scottish delicacy that I think involves stuffing like what?
这是一种苏格兰美食，我觉得里面塞了什么东西？
What do we hear?
我们听到了什么？
Pig liver?
猪肝？
Let's see this again.
我们再来看一遍。
So basically you take a sheep's liver, a heart, and a lung, and you put it inside the sheep's
基本上，你取羊的肝、心和肺，然后放进羊的
stomach and you serve that.
胃里，然后端上来。
And you cook it.
然后你把它煮熟。
Yeah, you cook it like that.
对，就这样煮。
You cook it.
你把它煮熟。
And so it's like all the insides of a sheep.
所以它就像羊的所有内脏。
Yeah.
是的。
It kind of sounds disgusting, but I'm pretty sure it tastes pretty good.
听起来有点恶心，但我很确定它味道不错。
It probably tastes good.
可能味道不错。
Because it's a Scottish delicacy, so eh.
因为它是苏格兰美食，所以嗯。
Yeah, I don't know.
是啊，我不知道。
Although I cannot imagine eating it in a chocolate.
虽然我无法想象把它放在巧克力里吃。
This is disgusting.
这太恶心了。
I've heard of countries where they take a chicken, they stuff it with something, like
我听说过有些国家，他们拿一只鸡，往里面塞东西，比如
they have a stuffing, and then they put the chicken inside a goat, and then the goat inside
有填料，然后把鸡放进山羊里，再把山羊放进
a bigger animal, and then they cook all that together.
更大的动物里，然后一起煮。
Oh, wow.
哦，哇。
And then you have this amazing, obviously it's huge, they use these big brick ovens
然后你得到这道惊人的菜，显然它很大，他们用那种大砖炉
to cook them, but you have this platter with three different types of meats.
来烤，但你有一个大盘子，上面有三种不同的肉。
Oh, wow.
哦，哇。
We have that in America.
美国也有这个。
Really?
真的吗？
It's called a turducken.
它叫turducken。
Turducken.
Turducken。
Turkey, ducken, turkey, duck, and chicken.
火鸡、鸭、火鸡、鸭和鸡。
So you have a chicken inside of a duck, which you put inside of a turkey.
所以你把一只鸡塞进鸭子里，再把鸭子塞进火鸡里。
Turkey, wow.
火鸡，哇。
And you bake it.
然后你烤它。
Wow, how does it taste?
哇，味道怎么样？
Delicious.
美味。
It's a very special taste.
味道很特别。
See?
看到了吧？
Exactly.
没错。
So if you want to know what your national delicacy is, do you have a delicacy in your
所以如果你想知道你的国家美食是什么，你的祖国
home country?
有美食吗？
Let us know on EnglishPod.com.
在EnglishPod.com上告诉我们。
We're always curious to talk about food, but we would love to have you practicing on the
我们总是对谈论食物充满好奇，但我们更希望你在
website and asking any questions that you may have.
网站上练习并提出任何问题。
That's right.
没错。
So we'll see everyone there.
那我们就在那里见大家。
Until next time.
下次再见。
Bye.
再见。